pwc.co.uk 2018-02-02

# Privacy Commitment

## Introduction

PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP (the UK firm) (“PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP” or “we”) is strongly committed to privacy issues, and this privacy statement details our approach on such issues. By using this site and submitting any personal data, you agree to the use by PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP of such data in accordance with this privacy statement. If you have questions on privacy issues, please email us at privacy@pwc.com.

## Data collection

We only collect identifiable personal data or information that is specifically and voluntarily provided by a visitor to our website. We receive limited identifiable information, such as name, title, company address, email address, and telephone and fax numbers, from website visitors.  Typically, identifying information is collected to:

  * Register for certain areas of the site
  * Enquire for further information
  * Distribute requested reference materials
  * Submit curriculum vitae

Visitors are also able to send email to us through the website. Their messages will contain the user’s screen name and email address, as well as any additional information the user may wish to include in the message

## Use of data

When a visitor provides personal data to us, we will use it for the purposes for which it was provided to us as stated at the point of collection (or as is obvious from the context of collection).  Examples of the types of use are given in the ‘data collection’ section above.  We may also use your data to contact you with information about PwC's business, services and events, and other information which may be of interest to you; you may unsubscribe from our mailing list at any time by contacting us as set out in the 'Unsubscribe' section below.

Our websites do not collect or compile personally identifying information for dissemination or sale to outside parties for consumer marketing purposes, or host mailings on behalf of third parties.

## Data controller

PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP (the limited liability partnership registered in England under registration no. OC303525 and with its registered address at 1 Embankment Place, London WC2N 6RH) is the data controller of any personal data collected through this website, and will process such data in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

## Disclosure to third parties

We recognise that your information is valuable and we take all reasonable measures to protect your information while it is in our care.

Personal data which has been submitted to PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP (UK firm) may be disclosed to other member firms in the PricewaterhouseCoopers network of firms where this is necessary to meet the purpose for which the visitor has submitted the information. Your personal information may also be transferred to third party service providers who process information on PwC's behalf, including providers of information technology, identity management, website hosting and management, data analysis, data back-up, security and storage services. As a result, your personal information may be transferred outside the country where you are located. This includes countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA) and countries that do not have laws that provide specific protection for personal information. By submitting personal data to this site, the visitor is providing explicit consent to the transfer of such data for the fulfilment of their voluntary requests.

PwC may disclose your personal information to law enforcement, regulatory, or other government agencies or to other third parties as required by, and in accordance with, applicable law or regulation.

Your personal information is not shared with any member firms in the PricewaterhouseCoopers network of firms, or shared with any third party, for any secondary or unrelated purposes unless otherwise disclosed at the point of collection. If there is an instance where such information may be shared, the visitor will be asked for permission beforehand.

## Security

We have implemented generally accepted standards of technology and operational security in order to protect personally identifiable data and information from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction. In particular, we ensure that all appropriate confidentiality obligations and technical and organisational security measures are in place to prevent any unauthorised or unlawful disclosure or processing of such information and data and the accidental loss or destruction of or damage to such information and data. Only authorised PricewaterhouseCoopers personnel are provided access to personally identifiable information and these employees have agreed to ensure confidentiality of this information. PricewaterhouseCoopers’ policy is to use secure socket layer technology for the protection of credit card information submitted through web forms.

## Access to information

If you would like to update any personal data you have submitted through this site, please do so via the original registration page or please email us at privacy@pwc.com.

When personally identifiable information is retained, we do not assume responsibility for verifying the ongoing accuracy of the content of personal information. When practically possible, if PricewaterhouseCoopers is informed that any personal data collected through a Web site is no longer accurate, PricewaterhouseCoopers will make appropriate corrections based on the updated information provided by the authenticated visitor.

If you would like details of the information which you have submitted to us through this site, you have a right of access to such information and you may contact us via the above email address. We may charge for a request for access in accordance with applicable legal requirements.

## Unsubscribe

Should visitors subsequently choose to unsubscribe from mailing lists or any registrations, we will provide instructions, on the appropriate webpage or in communications to our visitors, or a visitor may contact by email to privacy@pwc.com.

## Data retention

The personal data you submit to us will only be retained for as long as is required for the purposes for which it was collected or as required by law.

For example, contact information about visitors (such as information generated though registration for access to areas on the site) will be kept as long as the information is required to completely service the contact request or until a user requests that we delete that information. Mailing list information, discussion posts and email are kept for only the period of time considered reasonable to facilitate the visitor’s requests.

## Cookies

We use small text files called ‘cookies’ which are placed on your hard drives to assist in providing a more customised website experience. The use of cookies is now standard operating procedure for most websites. However if you are uncomfortable with the use of cookies, most browsers now permit users to opt-out of receiving them. In that case you will be unable to use this registration process and may find other functionality in the site impaired. After termination of the visit to our site, you can always delete the cookie from your system if you wish.
